{
  "courses": [
    null,
    {
      "name": "E business",
      "course_id": "1",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "EBUSINESS SUPPORT OFFICER",
        "basic_average": "CREDIT CARDS DEVELOPMENT",
        "basic_good": "WEB/COMMERCE DEVELOPMENT",
        "intermediate_below_average": "EBUSINESS SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "PREPAID CARD DEVELOPMENT",
        "intermediate_good": "EBUSINESS ASSURANCE AND COMPLIANCE",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT",
        "expert_good": "BUSINESS INTELLIGENCE"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Information Security",
      "course_id": "2",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "INFORMATION SECURITY SUPPORT",
        "basic_average": "CHANNEL MONITORING",
        "basic_good": "OPERATIONS ANALYSIS",
        "intermediate_below_average": "INFORMATION SECURITY SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "SYSTEM MONITORING",
        "intermediate_good": "SECURITY OPERATIONS",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "BUSINESS COMPLIANCE",
        "expert_good": "INFORMATION RISK ANALYSIS"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Retail Banking",
      "course_id": "3",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "CUSTOMER SERVICE SUPPORT",
        "basic_average": "FINANCIAL SERVICES SUPPORT",
        "basic_good": "RELATIONSHIP MANAGEMENT",
        "intermediate_below_average": "CUSTOMER SERVICE SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "BRANCH SERVICES MANAGEMENT",
        "intermediate_good": "BRANCH BUSINESS MANAGEMENT",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "AREA BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT",
        "expert_good": "REGIONAL BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Compliance",
      "course_id": "4",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "COMPLIANCE SUPPORT",
        "basic_average": "COMPLIANCE MONITORING",
        "basic_good": "SYSTEM SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_below_average": "COMPLIANCE RETAIL  SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "COMPLIANCE SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_good": "RISK ASSESSMENT",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "RISK ASSESSMENT",
        "expert_good": "BUSINESS ASSURANCE"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Foreign banking services",
      "course_id": "5",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "FOREIGN BANKING SUPPORT",
        "basic_average": "FOREIGN BANKING COMPLIANCE",
        "basic_good": "TRADE SERVICES",
        "intermediate_below_average": "FOREIGN BANKING SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "FUNDS TRANSFER",
        "intermediate_good": "RECONCILIATION",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "FUNDS TRANSFER",
        "expert_good": "RECONCILIATION"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Transaction banking",
      "course_id": "6",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "BRANCH TRANSACTION SUPPORT",
        "basic_average": "TRANSACTION SUPPORT",
        "basic_good": "DEMAND MANAGEMENT",
        "intermediate_below_average": "TRANSACTION SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "DEMAND MANAGEMENT",
        "intermediate_good": "TRANSACTION BANKING RECONCILIATION",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "TECHNICAL SALES",
        "expert_good": "BUSINESS ANALYSIS"
      }
    },
    {
      "name": "Money Transfer",
      "course_id": "7",
      "recommendation": {
        "basic_below_average": "FOREIGN BANKING SUPPORT",
        "basic_average": "FOREIGN BANKING COMPLIANCE",
        "basic_good": "TRADE SERVICES",
        "intermediate_below_average": "FOREIGN BANKING SUPPORT",
        "intermediate_average": "FUNDS TRANSFER",
        "intermediate_good": "RECONCILIATION",
        "expert_blow_average": "go_back_to_videos",
        "expert_average": "FUNDS TRANSFER",
        "expert_good": "RECONCILIATION"
      }
    }
  ],
  "pre_test": [
    {
      "question": "Which of these platforms are not used for Money transfer transactions?",
      "options": [
        "RIA",
        "Western Union",
        "Finacle",
        "Moneygram"
      ],
      "answer": "Finacle",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "MTCN stands for",
      "options": [
        "Money Transfer Control Number",
        "Money Transaction Concurrency Nomenclature",
        "Money Transfer Concurrency Number",
        "Main Transfer Control Nomenclature"
      ],
      "answer": "Money Transfer Control Number",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not an acceptable Identification card for Money Transfer?",
      "options": [
        "Voter’s card",
        "International passport",
        "Student ID card",
        "Bank Verification Number(BVN)"
      ],
      "answer": "Student ID card",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "The accepted percentage error for Inbound transaction is",
      "options": [
        "5%",
        "6%",
        "15%",
        "10%"
      ],
      "answer": "10%",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which countries must you the country and state when doing outbound transaction?(Choose the best option)",
      "options": [
        "UK, China , Vietnnam",
        "US, Mexico, Canada",
        "US,UK, Kenya",
        "US,Canada,South Africa"
      ],
      "answer": "US, Mexico, Canada",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of these is a way of classifying documents in financial organizations.",
      "options": [
        "Secret, Confidential, Internal use, Public",
        "Served, Confidential, Internal use, private",
        "Secret, Confidential, Internal use, Private",
        "Secret, Conserved, Internal , Private"
      ],
      "answer": "Secret, Confidential, Internal use, Public",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What Can Malware not Do?",
      "options": [
        "Capture and send sensitive information from your workstation to the hacker (key loggers)",
        "Download other malware",
        "Crash your workstation",
        "Provide links to useful information"
      ],
      "answer": "Provide links to useful information",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "Unauthorized and/or illegal computer trespass executed locally or remotely is called --------.",
      "options": [
        "Theft",
        "Malware",
        "Hacking",
        "Phishing"
      ],
      "answer": "Hacking",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "Tricking people to give out sensitive information is known as---",
      "options": [
        "Theft",
        "Social Engineering",
        "Malware",
        "Hacking"
      ],
      "answer": "Social Engineering",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these will you consider a strong password?",
      "options": [
        "Ugochukwu",
        "Ugochukwu12",
        "%ugo14Chukwu",
        "Ugo3$"
      ],
      "answer": "%ugo14Chukwu",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the full meaning of KYC?",
      "options": [
        "Kernel yardstick Compliance",
        "Know your compliance",
        "Know your customer",
        "Know your controls"
      ],
      "answer": "Know your customer",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the ID cards pay require a third party identification?",
      "options": [
        "Voter’s card",
        "International passport",
        "Bank Verification Number(BVN)",
        "Workplace ID"
      ],
      "answer": "Workplace ID",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does KYC imply?(Select all that applies)",
      "options": [
        "A financial institution checks the identity of a customer",
        "A financial institution checks the background of a customer",
        "A financial institution reports all customers that want to start a business relationship.",
        "A financial institution checks source of funds of potential and existing customers"
      ],
      "answer": "A financial institution checks the identity of a customer * A financial institution checks the background of a customer * A financial institution checks source of funds of potential and existing customers",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a KYC red flag?",
      "options": [
        "A customer that is reluctant to provide information",
        "A customer that does not have a primary Identification card",
        "Customers providing conflicting information",
        "Opening account with variations of the same name."
      ],
      "answer": "A customer that does not have a primary Identification card",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Enhanced due diligence should be done for",
      "options": [
        "Medium risk customers",
        "High risk customers",
        "Bank Verification Number(BVN)",
        "Low risk customers"
      ],
      "answer": "High risk customers",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not an electronic channel",
      "options": [
        "Internet banking",
        "Transfer form",
        "Automated telephone",
        "ATM network"
      ],
      "answer": "Transfer form",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Internet banking cannot be used to",
      "options": [
        "Withdraw money",
        "Transfer money",
        "Perform trade securities",
        "View account balance"
      ],
      "answer": "Withdraw money",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select problems that could be encountered when logging on internet banking platform",
      "options": [
        "Spoofing",
        "Data alteration",
        "Second - level authentication",
        "Eavesdropping"
      ],
      "answer": "Spoofing * Data alteration * Eavesdropping",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of these is not a type of ATM card",
      "options": [
        "Mastercard",
        "Visacard",
        "Bankcard",
        "Vervecard"
      ],
      "answer": "Bankcard",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "A firstbank card used on another bank’s terminal is regarded by the issuing bank as",
      "options": [
        "ON us transaction",
        "Remote-on-us transaction",
        "Not-on-us transaction",
        "Bank on us transaction"
      ],
      "answer": "Remote-on-us transaction",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Bank provides guarantees to approved Contractors for advance payments received for execution of contracts for……..",
      "options": [
        "CFF",
        "LPP",
        "Advanced Payment Gurantee",
        "Personal Loan"
      ],
      "answer": "Advanced Payment Gurantee",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "A credit facility designed to allow the customer access to funds whilst awaiting payment inflow from the Principal is called ----",
      "options": [
        "LPO",
        "Overdraft",
        "Personal Loan",
        "INVOICE DISCOUNTING FACILITY"
      ],
      "answer": "INVOICE DISCOUNTING FACILITY",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "The difference between a CFF and LPO is that the former requires",
      "options": [
        "Additional details",
        "Due diligence",
        "Value addition",
        "Financing"
      ],
      "answer": "Value addition",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "Alex is a relationship manager in a financial institution. Choose the risks he should watch out for when giving personal loan against salary.",
      "options": [
        "Repayment",
        "Diversion",
        "Termination of employment",
        "Insurance"
      ],
      "answer": "Repayment * Diversion * Termination of employment",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of these is not a type of bond:",
      "options": [
        "Performance bond",
        "Tender bond",
        "Custom bond",
        "Value bond"
      ],
      "answer": "Value bond",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "A set of services that a financial institution  offers to customers to enhance their ability to execute transactions such as the exchanges of good (Trade) and management of monetary flows can best be described as:",
      "options": [
        "Retail banking",
        "Transaction banking",
        "Electronic banking",
        "Cash banking"
      ],
      "answer": "Transaction banking",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a collection platform",
      "options": [
        "Autoreg",
        "Remitta",
        "Google",
        "Interswitch"
      ],
      "answer": "Google",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "A teller has done an error while processing an FIRS transaction which impacted on the till account but does not discover the error till 11am the following day. What is the best approach to resolving the problem?",
      "options": [
        "Reverse the transaction",
        "Escalate the issue",
        "Cancel the transaction",
        "Reinitiate the transaction."
      ],
      "answer": "Escalate the issue",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which companies manages Remitta and Autoreg?",
      "options": [
        "Systemspecs",
        "Interswitch",
        "Systemspecs and interswitch repectively",
        "Interswitch and systemspecs respectively"
      ],
      "answer": "Systemspecs and interswitch repectively",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "A bank that is authorized to collect revenue on behalf of the biller is ….",
      "options": [
        "Lead bank",
        "Issuing bank",
        "Collecting bank",
        "Transaction bank"
      ],
      "answer": "Collecting bank",
      "course_id": "7"
    }
  ],
  "main_test": [
    {
      "question": "A customer with 54678923 as the MTCN is likely going to use ------?",
      "options": [
        "RIA",
        "Western Union",
        "Moneygram",
        "transfast"
      ],
      "answer": "Moneygram",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Transfers older than 90days on Western Union Platform are called-----",
      "options": [
        "Purged transfer",
        "Stale Transfer",
        "Inactive Transfer",
        "Unreinstated transfer"
      ],
      "answer": "Purged transfer",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does a locked transaction in Moneygram imply?(click all that applies)",
      "options": [
        "Transfer viewed but not paid due to discrepancies",
        "The transaction is inconsistent but can be paid",
        "Transfer is locked to the agent location and must be paid there",
        "The platform is inactive"
      ],
      "answer": "Transfer viewed but not paid due to discrepancies * Transfer is locked to the agent location and must be paid there",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not an acceptable Identification card for Money Transfer?",
      "options": [
        "Voter’s card",
        "International passport",
        "Bank Verification Number(BVN)",
        "Workplace ID%"
      ],
      "answer": "Workplace ID",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "The accepted percentage error for Inbound transaction is",
      "options": [
        "10%",
        "6%",
        "15%",
        "5%"
      ],
      "answer": "10%",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these will you consider a strong password?",
      "options": [
        "%ugo14Chukwu",
        "Ugochukwu",
        "Ugochukwu12",
        "Ugo3$"
      ],
      "answer": "%ugo14Chukwu",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of these is a way of classifying documents in financial organizations",
      "options": [
        "Secret, Confidential, Internal use, Public",
        "Served, Confidential, Internal use, private",
        "Secret, Confidential, Internal use, Private",
        "Secret, Conserved, Internal , Private"
      ],
      "answer": "Secret, Confidential, Internal use, Public",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What Can Malware not Do?",
      "options": [
        "Capture and send sensitive information from your workstation to the hacker (key loggers)",
        "Download other malware",
        "Provide links to useful information",
        "Crash your workstation"
      ],
      "answer": "Provide links to useful information",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "The three keys to successful information security are  --------.",
      "options": [
        "Intellect, Technology and Policies",
        "Skills, Technology and Policies",
        "People, Process and technology",
        "Employees, training and Policies"
      ],
      "answer": "People, Process and technology",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "A possibility that a threat exploits a vulnerability in an asset and causes damage or loss to the asset.",
      "options": [
        "Theft",
        "Risk",
        "Vulnerability",
        "Threat"
      ],
      "answer": "Risk",
      "course_id": "2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What are the information to report for a suspicious transaction?(Select all that Applies)",
      "options": [
        "Information about the reporting entity",
        "Details about the person conducting or attempting to conduct the transaction",
        "Details of the transaction itself",
        "Details of transactions of the customer’s relations for the past ten years."
      ],
      "answer": "Information about the reporting entity * Details about the person conducting or attempting to conduct the transaction * Details of the transaction itself",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "A simplied Due diligence will be done for a?",
      "options": [
        "Dealer on jewellery",
        "Foreign  Financial company",
        "Supermarket",
        "Student"
      ],
      "answer": "Student",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does KYC imply?(Select all that applies)",
      "options": [
        "A financial institution checks the identity of a customer",
        "A financial institution checks the background of a customer",
        "A financial institution reports all customers that want to start a business relationship.",
        "A financial institution checks source of funds of potential and existing customers"
      ],
      "answer": "A financial institution checks the identity of a customer * A financial institution checks the background of a customer * A financial institution checks source of funds of potential and existing customers",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a KYC red flag?",
      "options": [
        "A customer that is reluctant to provide information",
        "A customer that does not have a primary Identification card",
        "Customers providing conflicting information",
        "Opening account with variations of the same name."
      ],
      "answer": "A customer that does not have a primary Identification card",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Enhanced due diligence should be done for",
      "options": [
        "Medium risk customers",
        "High risk customers",
        "Bank Verification Number(BVN)",
        "Low risk customers"
      ],
      "answer": "High risk customers",
      "course_id": "4"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not an electronic channel",
      "options": [
        "Internet banking",
        "Transfer form",
        "Automated telephone",
        "ATM network"
      ],
      "answer": "Transfer form",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "A firstbank card used on another bank’s terminal is regarded by the issuing bank as",
      "options": [
        "ON us transaction",
        "Remote-on-us transaction",
        "Not-on-us transaction",
        "Bank on us transaction"
      ],
      "answer": "Remote-on-us transaction",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Internet banking cannot be used to",
      "options": [
        "Withdraw money",
        "Transfer money",
        "Perform trade securities",
        "View account balance"
      ],
      "answer": "Withdraw money",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Select problems that could be encountered when logging on internet banking platform",
      "options": [
        "Spoofing",
        "Data alteration",
        "Second - level authentication",
        "Eavesdropping"
      ],
      "answer": "Spoofing * Data alteration * Eavesdropping",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of these is not a type of ATM card",
      "options": [
        "Mastercard",
        "Visacard",
        "Bankcard",
        "Vervecard"
      ],
      "answer": "Bankcard",
      "course_id": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "A credit facility designed to allow the customer access to funds whilst awaiting payment inflow from the Principal is called ----",
      "options": [
        "INVOICE DISCOUNTING FACILITY",
        "LPO",
        "Overdraft",
        "Personal Loan"
      ],
      "answer": "INVOICE DISCOUNTING FACILITY",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "The difference between a CFF and LPO is that the former requires",
      "options": [
        "Additional details",
        "Due diligence",
        "Value addition",
        "Financing"
      ],
      "answer": "Value addition",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "Bank provides guarantees to approved Contractors for advance payments received for execution of contracts for……..",
      "options": [
        "CFF",
        "LPP",
        "Advanced Payment Gurantee",
        "Personal Loan"
      ],
      "answer": "Advanced Payment Gurantee",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "One of these is not a type of bond:",
      "options": [
        "Performance bond",
        "Tender bond",
        "Custom bond",
        "Value bond"
      ],
      "answer": "Value bond",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which facility will you recommend against a customer's salary to meet his or her personal needs?",
      "options": [
        "CFF",
        "LPP",
        "Advanced Payment Gurantee",
        "Personal Loan against salary"
      ],
      "answer": "Personal Loan against salary",
      "course_id": "3"
    },
    {
      "question": "A set of services that a financial institution  offers to customers to enhance their ability to execute transactions such as the exchanges of good (Trade) and management of monetary flows can best be described as:",
      "options": [
        "Retail banking",
        "Transaction banking",
        "Electronic banking",
        "Cash banking"
      ],
      "answer": "Transaction banking",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these is not a collection platform",
      "options": [
        "Autoreg",
        "Remitta",
        "Google",
        "Interswitch"
      ],
      "answer": "Google",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "A teller has done an error while processing an FIRS transaction which impacted on the till account but does not discover the error till 11am the following day. What is the best approach to resolving the problem?",
      "options": [
        "Reverse the transaction",
        "Escalate the issue",
        "Cancel the transaction",
        "Reinitiate the transaction."
      ],
      "answer": "Escalate the issue",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which companies manages Remitta and Autoreg?",
      "options": [
        "Systemspecs",
        "Interswitch",
        "Systemspecs and interswitch repectively",
        "Interswitch and systemspecs respectively"
      ],
      "answer": "Systemspecs and interswitch repectively",
      "course_id": "7"
    },
    {
      "question": "A bank which funds collected from the collection banks are swept and warehoused is …..",
      "options": [
        "Lead bank",
        "Issuing bank",
        "Collecting bank",
        "Transaction bank"
      ],
      "answer": "Lead bank",
      "course_id": "7"
    }
  ],
  "staff": {
    "wan": {
      "category": "employee",
      "courses_assigned": [
        "1",
        "2"
      ],
      "lastname": "Doglas",
      "password": "12345",
      "staff_id": "wan",
      "surname": "John",
      "staff_manager_id": "jessica"
    },
    "cali": {
      "category": "employee",
      "courses_assigned": [
        "1",
        "3"
      ],
      "lastname": "Cali",
      "password": "12345",
      "staff_manager_id": "specter",
      "staff_id": "cali",
      "surname": "Ilo"
    },
    "specter": {
      "category": "manager",
      "lastname": "Harvey",
      "password": "12345",
      "staff_id": "specter",
      "surname": "Specter"
    },
    "jessica": {
      "category": "manager",
      "lastname": "Jessica",
      "password": "12345",
      "staff_id": "jessica",
      "surname": "Pearson"
    }
  }
}
